Guide to the Stephen Harmon Photographs 1942, 1968-2017 PR 362
New-York Historical Society
- Series D.III. New York City Buildings, Parks and Other Cityscapes (2002 and later), 2002-2017; 426.4 Megabytes (1571 digital images in JPG format)
  - Upper West Side, West 75th Street (4 photos + 1 email), 2016 August 9 (Digital folder 20160811, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
    Brownstones on the south side of West 75th between Columbus and Amsterdam avenues.
  - Various (7 photos + 2 emails), 2016 August 24 (Digital folder 20160824, Digital file 1_1-7, 2 emails)
    1)Chelsea. 18th Street and 6th Avenue looking northeast. 2) Midtown. Intersection of 7th Avenue and 38th Street.
  - Hudson Yards construction (1 photo +1 email), 2016 August 27 (Digital folder 20160902, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Greenwich Village. Cornelia Street between Bleecker Street and 6th Avenue (1 photo + 1 email), 2016 September 6 (Digital folder 20160910, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Upper West Side. Amsterdam Avenue at West 65th Street (1 photo +1 email), 2016 September 7 (Digital folder 20160912, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Metropolitan Opera House at Lincoln Center (14 photos + 1 email), 2016 September 23 (Digital folder 20160926, Digital file 1_01-14, email)
    Interior views of lobby and staircase (without people).
  - Midtown. 9th Avenue between 45th and 46th streets (2 photos + 2 emails), 2016 September 26 (Digital folder 20160926, Digital file 2_1-2, 2 emails)
  - Upper West Side. (2 photos + 2 emails), 2016 October (Digital folder 20161009, Digital file 2_1-2, 2 emails)
    1) Traffic on West 65th Street looking east between Amsterdam Avenue and Broadway. 2) Bus stop, east side of Amsterdam Avenue between 72nd and 73rd streets.
  - Grand Central Terminal, western facade (30 photos + 1 email), 2016 November 10 (Digital folder 20161110, Digital file 2_01-30, email)
    Photos taken when the facade was exposed in the time between the demolition of an adjoining building and the construction of a new building. Also includes views of the MetLife building.
  - Long Island City skyline/Citicorp Building (4 photos + 1 email), 2016 November 13 (Digital folder 20161120, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
    View across East River from Manhattan at 57th Street and Sutton Place.
  - Jackson Heights, Queens. Jax Inn Diner (3 photos + 1 email), 2016 December 14 (Digital folder 20161218, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
  - 125th Street (18 photos + 1 email), 2016 December (Digital folder 20161228, Digital file 1_01-18, email)
    Street scenes of: people, shop displays, storefronts, Apollo Theater marquee.
  - Upper West Side (2 photo + 1 email), 2016 December 30 (Digital folder 20161230, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    1) Time Warner Center at Columbus Center and 2) The Dorilton at Broadway and West 71st Street.
  - Upper West Side (4 photos + 1 email), 2017 January 4 (Digital folder 20170105, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
    Buildings on west side of Amsterdam Avenue between 75th and 77th streets.
  - Greenwich Village. Broadway looking north from mid block between W. 4th and Washington (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 January 14 (Digital folder 20170114, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Flatiron Building (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 January 14 (Digital folder 20170114, Digital file 4_1, email)
  - Greenwich Village. Washington Square North and the Arch (4 photos + 1 email), 2017 January 14 (Digital folder 20170115, Digital file 1_1-4, email)
  - Columbus Circle (21 photos + 3 emails), 2017 January 21 (Digital folder 20170121, Digital file 1_01-21, 3 emails)
    Views in and from the Robert Restaurant at top of the Museum of Art and Design at Columbus Circle (14), food cart (1), subway entrance signage (1), and across Columbus Circle from inside the Time Warner complex (5). Several of these photos include the Columbus statue and column.
  - Upper West Side. (3 photos + 1 email), 2017 January 21 (Digital folder 20170129, Digital file 1_1-3, email)
    Broadway looking south from 70th Street; Amsterdam Avenue looking north from 72nd Street; and north side of 72nd between Amsterdam and Columbus avenues.
  - Upper West Side (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 February 5 (Digital folder 20170205, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
    1) North side of West 80th Street between Amsterdam and Columbus avenues. 2) Beresford shot from Columbus Avenue about 80th Street looking northeast.
  - Lower Manhattan skyline (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 February 19 (Digital folder 20170219, Digital file 1_1, email)
    View south from terrace of Whitney Museum (Gansevoort Street).
  - Midtown. Park Avenue at 64th Street (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 February 22 (Digital folder 20170224, Digital file 3_1-2, email)
  - Upper West Side (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 February 24 (Digital folder 20170224, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    1) North side of 72nd Street between West End Avenue and Broadway. 2) 72nd Street looking east from just west of Broadway.
  - Greenwich Village/Meatpacking District. Hudson Street at Jane Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 March 30 (Digital folder 20170330, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Upper West Side (3 photos + 3 emails), 2017 April 8 (Digital folder 20170408, Digital file 2_1-3, 3 emails)
    1) View of 72d Street at Broadway and Amsterdam avenue; 2) Mitchell's liquors storefront; 3) Amsterdam Avenue, between 86th and 87th streets.
  - Lincoln Square Synagogue teardown (6 photos + 2 emails), 2017 April 10-12 (Digital folder 20170410, Digital file 1_1-6, 2 emails)
  - Greenwich Village (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 April (Digital folder 20170416, Digital folder 2_1-3, 2 emails)
    1) Christopher Street, from Bedford Street; 2) Lucille Lortel theater on Christopher; 3) Corner of 10th and Hudson streets.
  - North & south views from a terrace of the Whitney Museum (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 April 23 (Digital folder 20170423, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
  - Upper West Side. Central Park West, looking north from mid-70s (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 May? (Digital folder 20170514, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Hunter College. Walkways at 68th Street above Lexington Avenue (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 May 17 (Digital folder 20170518, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Union Square area. (2 photos + 2 emails), 2017 May 27 (Digital folder 20170528, Digital file 1_1-2, 2 emails)
    1) Old Town Bar, East 18th Street between Broadway and Park Avenue South; 2) Union Square farmers' market.
  - Manhattan skyline and Queens/Long Island City, from Long Island Expressway (19 photos + 2 emails), 2017 June 4 (Digital folder 20170604, Digital file 2_01-19, 2 emails)
    9 views from the LIE southwest toward the Freedom Tower (Lower Manhattan) or west into Midtown, with billboards for the lottery and Broadway show "Hamilton" in some. 10 views taken closer to the Midtown Tunnel that include views of construction in Long Island City, the Edward Koch Queensboro Bridge/59th Street Bridge, and midtown skyline. Taken in traffic on the LIE so provides car traffic/commuter view in some.
  - Times Square (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 June 6 (Digital folder 20170608, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    Views south and north from middle of 7th Avenue at 45th Street.
  - Central Park South skyline (5 photos + 1 email), 2017 June 7 (Digital folder 20170607, Digital file 1_1-5, email)
    Views from within the Park and from the roof garden of the Metropolitan Museum of Art
  - Lexington Avenue, looking south from 60th Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 June 14 (Digital folder 20170614, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - West End Avenue between 90th and 91st streets (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 June? (Digital folder 20170619, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
  - Throgs Neck Bridge and Whitestone Bridge (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 June 27 (Digital folder 20170629, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
    Aerial view from airplane.
  - Lower Manhattan. Foley Square / Chambers Street subway entrance (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 June (Digital folder 20170712, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Astoria, Queens. 31st Street at 24th Avenue and Elias Corner for Fish (2 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 6 (Digital folder 20170707, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Times Square area (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 17 (Digital folder 20170705, Digital file 1_1-3, 2 emails)
    Two images of 45th Street, east of 8th Avenue; one of crowd in Time Square.
  - Views from the terrace of the Whitney Museum (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 9 (Digital folder 20170709, Digital file 2_1-3, 2 emails)
    1 view north over the Meatpacking District toward Midtown skyscrapers and 2 across Hudson to New Jersey (Hoboken), including W Hotel and Hoboken Terminal.
  - Upper West Side (7 photos + 5 emails), 2017 July 16-18 (Digital folder 20170717, Digital file 1_1-7, 5 emails)
    1) Building under construction on the southwest corner of Broadway and 80th Street; 2) Broadway median at 80th Street, looking south; 3&4) Apthorp courtyard; 5&6) Dakota (newly cleaned); 7) Detail of iron railing sculpture at Dakota.
  - Times Square area (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 17 (Digital folder 20170717, Digital file 3_1-3, 2 emails)
    1) 7th Avenue at 49th Street; 2&3) Storefronts on Broadway at 50th Street.
  - Central Park. Central Park South skyline; "Imagine" mosaic at Strawberry Fields (3 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 18 (Digital folder 20170718, Digital file 4_1-3, 2 emails)
    Early morning view of the mosaic and surrounding benches with no people.
  - Midtown (8 photos + 3 emails), 2017 July 19 (Digital folder 20170721, Digital file 2_1-8, 3 emails)
    1) 58th Street between 5th and 6th avenues; 2) corner of 6th Avenue and 58th Street; 3-8) images taken within the Plaza Hotel on the set of a masked ball scene for the film "Pentagon Papers" (including self-portrait of Harmon, an extra, with and without costume).
  - Upper West Side (7 photos + 3 emails), 2017 July 22-23 (Digital folder 20170724, Digital file 1_1-7, 3 emails)
    1,2) Entrance gates at the Belnord; 3-5) West 72nd Street, north side, between Amsterdam and Columbus avenues; 6,7) 72nd Street subway station building.
  - Upper West Side (8 photos + 2 emails), 2017 July 30 (Digital folder 20170807, Digital file 1_1-8, 2 emails)
    Images of Amsterdam Avenue and 73rd, 74th, and 75th streets. looking south. The 4th image is from 73d looking south and the last is a NYC bus stop in mid block between 72d and 73d.
  - Skyline views from Lower Manhattan (7 photos + 3 emails), 2017 July (Digital folder 20170807, Digital file 2_1-7, 3 emails)
    Views taken from the 42nd floor of 75 Wall Street: 3 photos east to Brooklyn, one of the Brooklyn and Manhattan bridges, and 3 north toward the Municipal Building.
  - Chelsea / Flatiron area (17 photos + 9 emails), 2017 August (Digital folder 20170809, Digital file 1_01-17, 9 emails)
    1-3) 7th Avenue between 22nd and 23rd streets; 4) 7th Avenue between 20th and 21st streets; 5-8) 5th Avenue between 23rd and 24th streets; 9-13) food cart on 5th Avenue between 23rd and 24th streets; 14) detail of the facade of the Flatiron Building; 15) Bellevue Hospital at East 29th Street; 16) pedestrian mall/plaza in front of the Flatiron Building, looking north with Empire State Building in background; 17) west side of 5th Avenue between 23rd and 22nd Street with glimpse of the Flatiron Building and pedestrian mall/plaza.
  - Upper West Side. Riverside Boulevard from 69th Street (8 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 9 (Digital folder 20170810, Digital file 1_1-8, email)
  - Central Park (16 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 10 (Digital folder 20170810, Digital file 2_01-16, email)
    Morning views of Central Park South skyline, the Mall, Bethesda Terrace and Fountain, general views.
  - Lincoln Center (14 photos + 3 emails), 2017 August (Digital folder 20170810, Digital file 3_01-14, 3 emails)
    1-2) Juilliard School, from the Reflecting Pool in front of the Beaumont Theater; 3-7) Henry Moore sculptures in the Reflecting Pool with David Geffen Hall in the background; 8-11) Reflecting Pool and buildings at night; 12-14) 65th Street at night.
  - Queens skyline (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 8 (Digital folder 20170811, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    View across the East River from above the FDR Drive.
  - Midtown. 5th Avenue, north and south from 60th Street (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 12 (Digital folder 20170814, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
  - Upper West Side. Beacon Theater (3 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 13 (Digital folder 20170814, Digital file 2_1-3, email)
    One image of rear of theater on Amsterdam Avenue, two of front and marquee on Broadway.
  - SoHo / Bowery area (8 photos + 4 emails), 2017 August 20 (Digital folder 20170820, Digital file 1_1-8, 4 emails)
    Storefronts at the corner of Prince and Elizabeth streets (Quality Mending Co.) and along the Bowery, which includes the New Museum.
  - Upper West Side (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 August 21 (Digital folder 20170822, Digital file 3_1-2, email)
    Views from rooftop on Amsterdam Avenue: building at 76th Street and Amsterdam, and view north up Amsterdsm.
  - Lower Manhattan (7 photos + 3 emails), 2017 August 28 (Digital folder 20170828, Digital file 1_1-7, 3 emails)
    1-3) Freedom Tower, with Battery Place and bike path in foreground; 4-5) view across Hudson River of Jersey City waterfront and skyline; 6-7) building (Ocean Residences in 2021) at West Street off Battery Place.
  - SoHo / Bowery area (8 photos + 6 emails), 2017 September 1 (Digital folder 20170901, Digital file 2_1-8, 6 emails)
    1-2) Houston Street storefronts around Forsyth Street, including Yona Shimmel knish bakery; 3-4) basketball cage and playground at Stanton and Forsyth streets; 5) building on the southwest corner of Chrystie and Stanton streets; 6-7) Bowery around Prince Street; 8) West Broadway at Prince.
  - Chelsea / Third Cemetery of Congregation Shearith Israel (6 photos + 2 emails), 2017 September 3 (Digital folder 20170903, Digital file 1_1-6, 2 emails)
    One image of 6th Avenue between 21st and 22nd streets, and five images of the cemetery on 21st Street.
  - Mid/Upper East Side (2 photos + 1 email), 2017 September? (Digital folder 20170912, Digital file 1_1-2, email)
    FDR Drive north from 70th Street, and the northeast corner of 72nd Street and York Avenue.
  - Midtown. Hudson Yards construction (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 September 18 (Digital folder 20170918, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Midtown. 3rd Avenue looking north from 63rd Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 October 4 (Digital folder 20171005, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Upper West Side (7 photos + 4 emails), 2017 October (Digital folder 20171017, Digital file 1_1-7, 4 emails)
    1-5) Buildings on West 71st Street between Central Park West and Columbus to Amsterdam Avenues; 6) detail of ornamentation on one of the buildings; 7) reflection of San Remo towers in a Central Park pond.
  - Chelsea. 7th Avenue and 23rd Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 October 21 (Digital folder 20171023, Digital file 2_1, email)
  - Central Park. Entrance at Central Park West and 69th Street (1 photo + 1 email), 2017 October 31 (Digital folder 20171030, Digital file 2_1, email)
- Series D.IV. "Street Portraits", circa 1978-1988; 90.2 Megabytes (561 digital images in JPG format)
  The series includes 561 images transmitted to N-YHS in 35 emails by Stephen Harmon from 2012-2017 (though perhaps 5-10% are duplicates sent multiple times). As Harmon described these in his initial email, the photographs were "made of people I observed or directly confronted from about 1978 to 1985" in order to capture the distinctive look of the period. The series uses the title "Street Portraits" given to the photographs by Harmon, though he also often referred to the series in his emails as "Street People." That title was not used here as that term is commonly used to refer to homeless or other individuals who live on the streets. Although there do appear to be such individuals in the series, there is a greater variety of people in these photographs.
  The series includes portraits of a wide range of individuals and groups. These include the elderly, middle-aged, youths, and children; men and women; and various ethnicities. There are portraits of individuals, couples, and small groups. Many photos focus tightly on the face/head of the subject, while others are taken from a distance. Some focus on particular articles of clothing, such as torn ankle socks, or parts of a body, such as a tattooed arm. Many of the subjects are aware of the photographer and provide varied reactions, from smiles to belligerent glares. On the other hand, many photographs are candid shots.
  Some of the photographs depict people as they conduct their labor on the street, such as mailmen, bus drivers, musicians,and vendors. Some are tender, such as those of affectionate couples, or poignant, such as those of elderly couples supporting each other, or playful, such as the child in the spray of a fire hydrant. Most simply capture people as they engage with their life routines: standing at crosswalks, walking along sidewalks, sitting on park benches and stoops, reading newspapers at bus stops, or using telephone booths, and conversing with one another. Most of the shots are in outdoor/exterior spaces, but a few, usually taken from the sidewalk and through the storefront window, depict diners, barber shop patrons, and others.
  The diversity of clothing features prominently in the series. It ranges from conventional suits and ties to tattered apparel to the punk look of the era to various fashions, including hair styles, and casual streetwear. The photographs were taken in various seasons so the portraits range from the loosely-dressed look of the summer to the bundled overcoats of winter.
  Although the photographs are generally not associated with a very specific location, they are all from New York and likely from the Upper West Side/Central Park area through Midtown to Greenwich Village for the most part. The cityscape provides a backdrop to many of the photographs, including newstands, food carts, storefronts, parked and moving cars, taxis, and nondescript buildings. All in all, the photos capture a sense of the demographic diversity found day to day on the streets of Manhattan, and the particular look of that diversity in that period.
  Because of the consistency of the overall theme of the series, the individual emails generally include little or no additional context to the photographs, but there are a few exceptions to this.
  The series is arranged in the order in which the emails transmitting the photographs were received from 2012-2017.
  - Street Portraits (26 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20121002, Digital file 2_01-26, email)
  - Street Portraits (167 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20150409, Digital file 1_001-167, email)
  - Street Portraits (35 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160418, Digital file 1_01-35, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160424, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (5 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160504, Digital file 1_1-5, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160505, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160524, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160530, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160602, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160606, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160611, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160615, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
    One photo (folder/file: 20160615_1_06) is of the author, Tom Wolfe, smiling to the camera, photographed on 5th Avenue around 47th or 48th St.
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160712, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (9 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160725, Digital file 1_1-9, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160730, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160810, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160818, Digital file 1_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (12 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20160908, Digital file 1_01-12, email)
  - Street Portraits (12 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20161009, Digital file 3_01-12, email)
  - Street Portraits (14 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20161028, Digital file 1_01-14, email)
  - Street Portraits (12 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20161109, Digital file 1_01-12, email)
  - Street Portraits (12 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20161211, Digital file 1_01-12, email)
  - Street Portraits (18 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20161220, Digital file 1_01-18, email)
  - Street Portraits (21 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170102, Digital file 1_01-21, email)
  - Street Portraits (15 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170111, Digital file 1_01-15, email)
  - Street Portraits (15 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170122, Digital file 1_01-15, email)
  - Street Portraits (19 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170205, Digital file 1_01-19, email)
  - Street Portraits (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1985 (Digital folder 20170305, Digital file 1_1, email)
    Includes photo of a man with tattooed arm. The photo was also sent in email 29 (next), but the email that forwarded this copy provides some additional context.
  - Street Portraits (10 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170305, Digital file 2_01-10, email)
  - Street Portraits (11 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170407, Digital file 1_01-11, email)
  - Street Portraits (2 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170423, Digital file 2_1-2, email)
  - Street Portraits (12 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170508, Digital file 1_01-12, email)
  - Street Portraits (11 photos + 1 email), circa 1978-1985 (Digital folder 20170601, Digital file 1_01-11, email)
  - Street Portraits (1 photo + 1 email), circa 1982 (Digital folder 20170901, Digital file 1_1, email)
  - Street Portraits (1 photo + 1 email), 1988 November (Digital folder 20171018, Digital file 1_1, email)
- Series D.V. New York City "Street Show", 1995-2017; 11.2 Megabytes (18 digital images in JPG format)